Susan Rindt, PsyD

Markdown -> PDF, HTML, and more http://github.com/drrindt/resume

SUMMARY

I am an independent consultant for several organizations providing case consultation, training seminars and program development services. My clinical interests and expertise include: trauma (combat, personal sexual assault, child physical and sexual abuse); acute psychiatric disorders; grief and loss; substance abuse; relationship issues and communication patterns; anxiety and eating disorders; specific learning difficulties; and adolescent, developmental, and disorders of childhood.

I also maintain a private clinical practice while continuing to provide treatment services and consultation supervision in both hospital and community-based settings. At this time I provide individual therapy, group therapy, and psychological testing services to diverse populations.

EDUCATION

California School of Professional Psychology (San Diego, CA)

Psy.D. Clinical Psychology—Family Track, March 2002

California School of Professional Psychology (San Diego, CA)

M.A. Clinical Psychology, June 2000

University of Stirling (Scotland, UK)

B.Sc. Psychology, First class distinction, June 1998

Certifications

- ► Certified Prolonged Exposure Therapy clinician
- ► Additional specialist training in Cognitive Processing Therapy and EMDR

CLINICAL EXPERIENCE

Director of Military Programs, April 2008—present

Contractor to Aurora Behavioral Healthcare, San Diego, CA

- ► Program development, organization and management of intensive inpatient residential treatment program for active duty service members and their families.
- ► Manage a staff of 15 directly and oversee operations of multiple other departments.
- ► Provide direct therapy treatment for PTSD and co-occurring substance use disorders as well as multiple psychiatric and personality disorders.
- Clinical supervision and training of licensed professionals working in this program.
- ► Administrative duties including department accounting, case management, treatment team, utilization review, business development and assisting in personnel decisions.
- ► FIXME: Marketing and outreach to military bases through the western United States, Alaska, and Hawaii.
- Development, outreach, and business development to military personnel

- Liaison between nursing staff, social work department, utilization review, psychiatrists, and the psychology department
- ► **FIXME**: some mention of working with military insurers (Tricare, etc)
- Research project development and trial on programmatic ?FIXME? and new initiatives and conjunction with UCSD, VA, SDSU and location MFTs.

Director of Psychology, April 2007—present

Contractor to Aurora Behavioral Healthcare, San Diego, CA

- ► Clinical supervision and training of 9 predoctoral and 3 postdoctoral interns in group therapy, individual therapy, testing batteries, and initial assessment in an acute psychiatric population.
- Group and individual therapy with acute inpatient and outpatient psychiatric patients.
- Administrative duties including departmental accounting, case management, treatment team, utilization review, and assisting in personnel decisions. Liaison between nursing staff, social work department, utilization review, psychiatrists, and the psychology department.

Clinical Private Practice/Hospital Consultant, August 2003—present

Locations: Coronado, CA / Del Mar, CA / Vista, CA

- ► *Treatment modalities*: Individual psychotherapy using a variety of therapeutic techniques including cognitive behavioral therapy, family systems theory, and insight-oriented modalities. Brief therapy and long term models used where appropriate.
- Consulting and Training Services: Individual psychotherapy using a variety of therapeutic techniques
 including cognitive behavioral therapy, family systems theory, and insight-oriented modalities.
 Brief therapy and long term models used where appropriate
- ► Hospital Privileges: Aurora Behavioral Health Care

Assistant Director of Psychological Services, August 2003—January 2004

Alvarado Parkway Institute, La Mesa, CA

- ► Clinical supervision and training of 6 predoctoral and 3 postdoctoral interns in group therapy, individual therapy, testing batteries, and initial assessment.
- Group and individual therapy with acute inpatient and outpatient psychiatric patients.
- ▶ Administrative duties including departmental accounting, case management, treatment team, utilization review, and assisting in personnel decisions. Liaison between nursing staff, social work department, utilization review, psychiatrists, and the psychology department.

Psychological Assistant, August 2002—January 2003

Alvarado Parkway Institute, La Mesa, CA

- Group and individual therapy with acute psychiatric patients.
- ► Training and supervision of psychology interns.
- Case management using a multidisciplinary team approach. Psychological testing batteries.
- Liaison between nursing, social work, utilization review, psychiatrists, and psychology departments.

Psychological Assistant, September 2001—August 2002

Switzer Center School, Torrance, CA

- ► Individual counseling with learning disabled and emotionally disturbed children and adolescents.
- Case management. Achievement and neuropsychological testing.

- ► Individual education program development.
- ► Parent and collateral contact liaison.

Psychology Intern, July 2000—June 2001

Bayview Hospital, Chula Vista, CA

- Group and individual therapy with acute psychiatric patients.
- ► Case management using a multidisciplinary team approach. Psychological testing batteries.

Psychology Practicum, August 1999—June 2000

EYE Crisis and Counseling, San Marcos, CA

- ► Individual and group therapy with children, adults, and families primarily involving issues of sexual abuse.
- Psychological testing.
- ► Administrative functions.

GENERAL EXPERIENCE

Founding Member, Vice President and CFO, July 2010—Present

P.A.T.H.S., Psychiatric And Therapeutic Health Services, Inc., Del Mar, CA

- ► Managing partner of a clinical mental health group practice serving primarily military spouses and families.
- ► Responsible for clinical oversight, marketing, and day-to-day operations
- ► Financial management and accounting

Assistant Manager, August 1989—March 1993

B & Q, Plc., Glasgow, Scotland, UK

- ► Personnel, administration, and systems manager.
- ► Responsible for 70 staff and 54,000 sq. ft. of retail space.
- ► Staff trainer. **FIXME**: Expand

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant, August 1999—May 2001

California School of Professional Psychology (San Diego)

- ► Dissertation Orientation
- ► Developmental Psychology
- ► Social Psychology

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Trauma Related Guilt Reduction (TRG-R), FIXME: Dates

With VA Hospital, UC San Diego and Aurora Behavioral Healthcare

► Clinical treatment protocol addressing treatment resistant guilt in OIF/OEF combat service members.

Computerized Treatment for PTSD symptom reduction, FIXME: Dates

With SDSU, VA Hospital, UC San Diego, and Aurora Behavioral Healthcare

► Clinical treatment protocol for anxiety aspect of PTSD and the relationship to symptom severity

Efficacy of PTSD treatments in the inpatient setting, FIXME: Dates

With Aurora Behavioral Health Care, San Diego, CA

 Clinical assessments, diagnosis and treatment longitudinal outcome study of over 700 OIF/OEF service members

Sudden Sibling Loss FIXME:

AWARDS

San Diego Mental Health Community Honoree, 2009

► FIXME: For Development of Best Military Treatment Program

Best 24-hr Military Treatment Program

► FIXME:

BEST Scholarship

BUNAC, London, UK, 1998—2000

► Won \$10,000 scholarship for two years of post-graduate study in the United States from the British Universities North America Club (BUNAC).

Education Abroad Program (EAP) Participant

University of Stirling, Scotland, UK, 1996—1997

► Won fully funded scholarship (tuition and expenses) to study psychology overseas at the University of California, Irvine for one year.

ADDITIONAL CERTIFICATIONS AND CONTINUING EDUCATION

FIXME: all your military CEs

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

American Psychological Association

British Psychological Society

California Psychological Association

San Diego Psychological Association